<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on </title>
    <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kfrankc.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A lesson in humility</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lesson-in-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lesson-in-humility/</guid>
      <description>Before game 5 of the 2021 NBA Finals between the Milwaukee Bucks and the Phoenix Suns, the 26 year-old Bucks power forward Giannis Antetokounmpo gave a very reflective and insightful response to a question about his work ethics.
Paraphrased below, but highly recommend watching the entire video
&amp;ldquo;When you focus on the past, that&amp;rsquo;s your ego. When you focus on the future, that&amp;rsquo;s your pride. When you focus on the present, that&amp;rsquo;s your humility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>张一鸣 quotes</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/zhangyiming-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/zhangyiming-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Zhang Yiming (张一鸣) is the billionaire founder of Chinese internet company ByteDance, which develops a variety of apps, including the short-form video sharing platform TikTok. In his early 30s, while building his first startup, Zhang was also a prolific blogger, leaving a lot of his thoughts on work ethics, life philosophy, and relationship management on Weibo. These snippets from the early 2010s are especially interesting to look at now, considering his success in building a valuable technology giant in the post-Baidu, post-Alibaba, and post-Tencent tech landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Films &amp; TV in quarantine</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/film-tv-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/film-tv-2020/</guid>
      <description>Tenet - A SciFi action-thriller that is best digested via multiple viewings while perusing Reddit discussions.
Nightcrawler - A neo-noir psychological-thriller with a highlight performance from Jake Gyllenhaal as a creepy, tenacious photojournalist.
The Irishman - An epic crime film that is well worth the extended 209-min runtime, with themes that echo Scorsese&amp;rsquo;s 1990 film, Goodfellas.
Uncut Gems - A crime-thriller that kept me on the edge of my seats and my heart pounding from start to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy-load images</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lazy-load-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lazy-load-images/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in improving the performance of my website, especially on the &amp;lsquo;Drawings&amp;rsquo; page, where I showcase some of my artwork. Images are often the most common cause of poor website performance, due to their large file size. I found a neat tool called Lighthouse that helps debug performance issues and provide suggestions for improvements.
I ran Lighthouse on the previous version of my drawings page, and got the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/pandas-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/pandas-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Pandas is a comprehensive Python library for data analysis, but its syntax for performing certain specific data transformations can be difficult to discern from its documentation. I recently used Pandas in my analysis of Billboard Top 100 Music data, and I&amp;rsquo;ve uncovered several useful commands that I will most likely use again in the future, so I&amp;rsquo;m compiling a (growing) list here for both my own reference and the benefit of someone else struggling with these problems in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Jekyll portfolio</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/jekyll-masonry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/jekyll-masonry/</guid>
      <description>I built this site using Hugo. I built the previous version using Jekyll and Masonry
My first experience using Jekyll for building a personal website was with academicpages, which is an excellent theme that is mostly catered to, as you guessed, people in academia: it included many built-in front matter to list papers, publications, and talks.
I later switched to Minimal Mistakes, which is theme academicpages forked from. MM offered more opportunities for customizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational algebra &amp; SQL</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/query-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/query-languages/</guid>
      <description>Query languages (computer languages used to make queries in databases) are abundant in style and usage today. In 2018, Microsoft released Azure Data Explorer to GA, introducing another query language that is specifically optimized for semi-structured, unstructured, and time-series data. Even though we have many querying language options, they are all grounded in a field of mathematics called relational algebra.
Relational Algebra is an algebra where operands are defined as relations, or variables that represent relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Year @ Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lessons-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lessons-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>This was originally published on LinkedIn .
As 2018 comes to a close, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some of the lessons I learned this past year as a Program Manager at Microsoft. These opinions and observations are my own, and should be taken with the understanding that everyone&amp;rsquo;s professional journey is different. Some of these apply directly to the Program Management discipline, while others apply to anyone starting their first full-time job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurtosis of standard normal</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/kurtosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/kurtosis/</guid>
      <description>The Kurtosis of a random variable $X$ is the fourth moment of $X$. For a normal distribution, we often see it in the textbook as:
$$ \begin{align}\label{kurt} Kurt(X) = E\left[\left(\frac{X-\mu}{\sigma}\right)^4\right] - 3 \end{align} $$
My textbook explains:
&amp;ldquo;We subtract $3$ to make any Normal distribution have kurtosis $0$ &amp;quot;
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how $E\left[\left(\frac{X-\mu}{\sigma}\right)^4\right]$ is calculated to be 3. I will attempt to derive this solution.
Assumptions
The Normal Distribution has Probability Density Function (PDF):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deriving the normal distribution</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/normal-dist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/normal-dist/</guid>
      <description>In every introductory statistics class, we learned about the normal distribution, which has Probability Density Function (PDF):
$$ \tag{1} f(x | \mu, \sigma^2) = \frac{1}{\sqrt{2\pi \sigma^2}}e^{-\frac{(x-\mu)^2}{2\sigma^2}} $$
This looks like a fairly complicated equation, but the resulting graph (shown above) has some very cool properties (integrates to 1, represents real-valued random variables whose distributions are not known etc&amp;hellip;). I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how this is derived, and I finally found some answers via great videos and online forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lukas Graham &amp; 汪峰</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lukas-wangfeng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/lukas-wangfeng/</guid>
      <description>Last night at home, I heard Chinese singer 汪峰’s hit song from 2017, titled &amp;lsquo;那年我五岁&amp;rsquo; (That year when I was five), and surprisingly, I found that the lyrics and even the music video parallels the song &amp;lsquo;7 Years&amp;rsquo; from Danish band Lukas Graham. After scrolling through the Internet, I have yet to find anyone else juxtaposing these two songs; henceforth, here’s my take:
&amp;lsquo;7 Years&amp;rsquo; is a single from Lukas Graham’s second studio album, released on September 15, 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Panther</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/black-panther/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/black-panther/</guid>
      <description>A great film consists not only of a great cast, but also a great director, screenwriter, composer, cinematographer, and costume designer.
Black Panther is recieving critical acclaim, and here are some of the amazing people who made this film great.
Director
Ryan Coogler is a visionary man. Just look at how he deconstructs a complicated fight sequence from the film in terms of both the action and the symbolism. Coogler is not merely making another superhero film; he’s using his platform to tell the story about a fictional African nation uninterrupted by colonialism, a stand-alone film not dependent on others in the Marvel cinematic universe, and a narrative about multiple strong, independent female characters in an action-focused film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human learning &amp; intelligence</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/human-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/human-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading Prof. Song-Chun Zhu’s 60K+ character article on Artificial Intelligence (AI) over the holidays. One part of Prof. Zhu’s essay that caught my attention was Section 4, where he discusses the cognitive framework of AI research.
In the prior section, Prof. Zhu gives an extended example of a common crow that not only learned how to take advantage of passing cars to crack open nuts for the bird to eat, but also intentionally dropping the nut on pedestrian crosswalks so that the bird won’t be run over by vehicles as it swoops down to eat the nut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We should all learn Chinese</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/learn-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/learn-chinese/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago, my dad sent me a very long WeChat article, titled “浅谈人工智能：现状、任务、构架与统一 | 正本清源”.
Loosely translated, the title reads: “A light discussion of Artificial Intelligence: Current Situation, Purpose, Framework, and Unification | Finding the root of the issue”
The PI I used to do undergraduate research for — Prof. Song-Chun Zhu — wrote this 20,000+ character article. Prof. Zhu leads the Vision, Cognition, Learning, and Autonomy Lab at the University of California, Los Angeles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commencement speech</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/ucla-commencement-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/ucla-commencement-speech/</guid>
      <description>On June 17, 2017, I had the honor to speak about what being an Engineer means to me in front of 10,000+ people in Pauley Pavilion, at the 2017 UCLA Engineering Commencement for PhDs, Masters, and Bachelors degree recipients. As the Commencement Student Speaker, I wanted to find a voice that resonates with all Engineers, and so I focused on the qualities that applies to all of us moving forward: Mentorship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>左宗棠</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/chinese-life-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/chinese-life-advice/</guid>
      <description>I completed my undergraduate degree this past June. Like many new grads preparing to work in industry, I feel nervous about making a smooth transition from being a student to being a working-class young adult. Where do I go from here? How do I live a good life?
Last night, I found some reassurance in a quote by a Chinese official in the 清 (Qīng) Dynasty.
The story starts with a typical post-dinner discussion with my dad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 qualities of self-worth</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/self-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/self-worth/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago, my dad sent me a link to an excellent blog entry written in Mandarin Chinese. I have always loved the Chinese language for its elegant brevity, and this entry was no exception. In just a few lines of characters, it succinctly summarized 3 qualities of self-worth. I wanted to share this with my friends in the United States, so I decided to translate the entry into English:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Jon</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/jon-stewart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/jon-stewart/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The best defense against bullshit is vigilance. So if you smell something, say something.&amp;rdquo; — Jon Stewart
On Thursday, Comedy Central bid its final farewell to comedian Jon Stewart on The Daily Show. For 16 years, Jon scrutinized media, politicians, scandals, tragedies, and various controversies, using humor as his medium to give Americans a second lens into the world we live in today.
I was not there to watch The Daily Show in the very beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning 20</title>
      <link>https://kfrankc.com/writing/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kfrankc.com/writing/20/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, my parents celebrated my birthday early, because I’ll be at college during my actual birthday later in January. Usually, I reflect about being 1 year older AFTER my birthday, but since I’ve been having this ‘early celebration’ for a while, so I thought I’ll jot down some of my thoughts about the big two-zero now.
 Turning 20 is amazing. The moment when the tens-digit of your age changes is always a milestone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>