<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frank Chen on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frank Chen on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Films &amp; TV in 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12879624/&#34;&gt;Josee, the Tiger and the Fish&lt;/a&gt; - A romantic comedy drama anime with a beautiful score &amp;amp; some unexpected twists &amp;amp; turns&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1877830/&#34;&gt;The Batman&lt;/a&gt; - Robert Pattinson gives a nuanced portrayal of the titular character during his early days of being a vigilante, with an equally powerful performance from Paul Dano as the Riddler&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2953050/&#34;&gt;Encanto&lt;/a&gt; - The 60th film produced by Walt Disney animation studio, Encanto delivers a multifaceted story about the importance of family &amp;amp; acceptance, along with some Billboard top-charting songs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 1 year at Twitter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/twtr-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/twtr-one-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks 1 year working at Twitter 🎉 I&amp;rsquo;ve met &amp;amp; worked with so many smart, passionate tweeps here, both virtually &amp;amp; in person. It is gratifying to work on improving a product that I use every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In true Twitter fashion, of course I had to share my learnings via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kfrchen/status/1557007439958257664&#34;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publishing full text below as well:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Celebrating 1 yr @Twitter ✅ working on improving a product that I use every day has been both a challenging &amp;amp; rewarding experience&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Films &amp; TV in quarantine (part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5918982/&#34;&gt;Possessor&lt;/a&gt; - A scifi horror that blends the &amp;lsquo;sleeve&amp;rsquo; technology concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2261227/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;Altered Carbon&lt;/a&gt; with the cosmic suspense of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2085059/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1070874/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/a&gt; - A historical legal drama with director/writer Aaron Sorkin&amp;rsquo;s iconic fast-paced dialogues and an ensemble cast, including Succession&amp;rsquo;s Jeremy Strong (I didn&amp;rsquo;t even recognize him as Jerry Rubin!)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0390384/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;Primer&lt;/a&gt; - An indie scifi with an extremely low budget ($7K!), and showcases perhaps the most convoluted time travel plotline I have ever seen in film (had to watch it a few times to understand)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A lesson in humility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/lesson-in-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/lesson-in-humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before game 5 of the 2021 NBA Finals between the Milwaukee Bucks and the Phoenix Suns, the 26 year-old Bucks power forward Giannis Antetokounmpo gave a very reflective and insightful response to a question about his work ethics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paraphrased below, but highly recommend watching the entire &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-qLchg4xkOY&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you focus on the past, that&amp;rsquo;s your ego. When you focus on the future, that&amp;rsquo;s your pride. When you focus on the present, that&amp;rsquo;s your humility.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Antetokounmpo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>张一鸣 quotes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/zhangyiming-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/zhangyiming-quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zhang Yiming (张一鸣) is the billionaire founder of Chinese internet company ByteDance, which develops a variety of apps, including the short-form video sharing platform TikTok. In his early 30s, while building his first startup, Zhang was also a prolific blogger, leaving a lot of his thoughts on work ethics, life philosophy, and relationship management on Weibo. These snippets from the early 2010s are especially interesting to look at now, considering his success in building a valuable technology giant in the post-Baidu, post-Alibaba, and post-Tencent tech landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Films &amp; TV in quarantine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/film-tv-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6723592/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Tenet&lt;/a&gt; - A SciFi action-thriller that is best digested via multiple viewings while perusing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/tenet/&#34;&gt;Reddit discussions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2872718/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;Nightcrawler&lt;/a&gt; - A neo-noir psychological-thriller with a highlight performance from Jake Gyllenhaal as a creepy, tenacious photojournalist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1302006/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;The Irishman&lt;/a&gt; - An epic crime film that is well worth the extended 209-min runtime, with themes that echo Scorsese&amp;rsquo;s 1990 film, &lt;em&gt;Goodfellas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5727208/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&#34;&gt;Uncut Gems&lt;/a&gt; - A crime-thriller that kept me on the edge of my seats and my heart pounding from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazy-load images</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/lazy-load-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/lazy-load-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in improving the performance of my website, especially on the &amp;lsquo;Drawings&amp;rsquo; page, where I showcase some of my artwork. Images are often the most common cause of poor website performance, due to their large file size. I found a neat tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse/&#34;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; that helps debug performance issues and provide suggestions for improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I ran Lighthouse on the previous version of my drawings page, and got the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandas tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/pandas-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/pandas-tricks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pandas is a comprehensive Python library for data analysis, but its syntax for performing certain specific data transformations can be difficult to discern from its documentation. I recently used Pandas in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kfrankc/data512-final-project&#34;&gt;analysis of Billboard Top 100 Music data&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve uncovered several useful commands that I will most likely use again in the future, so I&amp;rsquo;m compiling a (growing) list here for both my own reference and the benefit of someone else struggling with these problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Jekyll portfolio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/jekyll-masonry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/jekyll-masonry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I built this site using Hugo. I built the previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kfrankc/kfrankc.github.io/releases&#34;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt; using Jekyll and Masonry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first experience using Jekyll for building a personal website was with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/academicpages/academicpages.github.io&#34;&gt;academicpages&lt;/a&gt;, which is an excellent theme that is mostly catered to, as you guessed, people in academia: it included many built-in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/front-matter/&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; to list papers, publications, and talks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I later switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&#34;&gt;Minimal Mistakes&lt;/a&gt;, which is theme academicpages forked from. MM offered more opportunities for customizations. It was around this time when I started to think about creating a custom home page to show some of my artwork and other engineering projects. I used to have this portfolio page done in pure HTML and CSS in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kfrankc/kfrankc.github.io/releases&#34;&gt;personal website v1&lt;/a&gt;, but with Jekyll, I figured the effort to refactor will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relational algebra &amp; SQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/query-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/query-languages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AnanthaRajuCprojects/List-of-programming-language-lists/blob/master/Query%20language.md&#34;&gt;Query languages&lt;/a&gt; (computer languages used to make queries in databases) are abundant in style and usage today. In 2018, Microsoft released &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/data-explorer/&#34;&gt;Azure Data Explorer&lt;/a&gt; to GA, introducing another query language that is specifically optimized for semi-structured, unstructured, and time-series data. Even though we have many querying language options,  they are all grounded in a field of mathematics called &lt;em&gt;relational algebra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relational Algebra is an algebra where operands are defined as relations, or variables that represent relations. This is why relational algebra provides the basis for a query language in relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Year @ Microsoft</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/lessons-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/lessons-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was originally published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lessons-from-1-year-microsoft-frank-chen/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As 2018 comes to a close, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some of the lessons I learned this past year as a Program Manager at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/microsoft/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. These opinions and observations are my own, and should be taken with the understanding that everyone&amp;rsquo;s professional journey is different. Some of these apply directly to the Program Management discipline, while others apply to anyone starting their first full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurtosis of standard normal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/kurtosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/kurtosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kurtosis of a random variable $X$ is the fourth moment of $X$. For a normal distribution, we often see it in the textbook as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$&#xA;\begin{align}\label{kurt}&#xA;Kurt(X) = E\left[\left(\frac{X-\mu}{\sigma}\right)^4\right] - 3&#xA;\end{align}&#xA;$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My textbook explains:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We subtract $3$ to make any Normal distribution have kurtosis $0$ &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how $E\left[\left(\frac{X-\mu}{\sigma}\right)^4\right]$ is calculated to be 3. I will attempt to derive this solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Normal Distribution has Probability Density Function (PDF):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deriving the normal distribution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/normal-dist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/normal-dist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/74/Normal_Distribution_PDF.svg/525px-Normal_Distribution_PDF.svg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Normal Distribution&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In every introductory statistics class, we learned about the normal distribution, which has Probability Density Function (PDF):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$&#xA;\tag{1} f(x | \mu, \sigma^2) = \frac{1}{\sqrt{2\pi \sigma^2}}e^{-\frac{(x-\mu)^2}{2\sigma^2}}&#xA;$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This looks like a fairly complicated equation, but the resulting graph (shown above) has some very cool properties (integrates to 1, represents real-valued random variables whose distributions are not known etc&amp;hellip;). I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how this is derived, and I finally found some answers via great &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cTyPuZ9-JZ0&#34;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/384893/how-was-the-normal-distribution-derived&#34;&gt;online forums&lt;/a&gt;. I will give an overview of the derivation here, based on YouTuber Mathoma&amp;rsquo;s amazing video (linked above).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lukas Graham &amp; 汪峰</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/lukas-wangfeng/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/lukas-wangfeng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night at home, I heard Chinese singer 汪峰’s hit song from 2017, titled &amp;lsquo;那年我五岁&amp;rsquo; (That year when I was five), and surprisingly, I found that the lyrics and even the music video parallels the song &amp;lsquo;7 Years&amp;rsquo; from Danish band Lukas Graham. After scrolling through the Internet, I have yet to find anyone else juxtaposing these two songs; henceforth, here’s my take:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;7 Years&amp;rsquo; is a single from Lukas Graham’s second studio album, released on September 15, 2015. It topped at #2 at Billboard Hot 100, and was nominated for three Grammy Awards: Record of the Year, Song of the Year, and Best Pop Duo/Group Performance. &amp;lsquo;那年我五岁&amp;rsquo; is 汪峰’s latest single, released on October 12, 2017. 汪峰 actually took a 5 month break from performances and concerts to concentrate and work on this song. It is a very long song, clocking in at 10 minutes 45 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Panther</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/black-panther/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/black-panther/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great film consists not only of a great cast, but also a great director, screenwriter, composer, cinematographer, and costume designer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latimes.com/entertainment/movies/la-et-mn-black-panther-reactions-20180218-story.html&#34;&gt;Black Panther is recieving critical acclaim&lt;/a&gt;, and here are some of the amazing people who made this film great.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Director&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ryan Coogler is a visionary man. Just look at how he &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SNHc2PxY8lY&#34;&gt;deconstructs a complicated fight sequence&lt;/a&gt; from the film in terms of both the action and the symbolism. Coogler is not merely making another superhero film; he’s using his platform to tell the story about a fictional African nation uninterrupted by colonialism, a stand-alone film not dependent on others in the Marvel cinematic universe, and a narrative about multiple strong, independent female characters in an action-focused film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human learning &amp; intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/human-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/human-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading Prof. Song-Chun Zhu’s 60K+ character &lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/-wSYLu-XvOrsST8_KEUa-Q&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on Artificial Intelligence (AI) over the holidays. One part of Prof. Zhu’s essay that caught my attention was Section 4, where he discusses the cognitive framework of AI research.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the prior section, Prof. Zhu gives an extended example of a common crow that not only learned how to take advantage of passing cars to crack open nuts for the bird to eat, but also intentionally dropping the nut on pedestrian crosswalks so that the bird won’t be run over by vehicles as it swoops down to eat the nut. Prof. Zhu postulates that the crow’s intelligence is a direct product of both its physical environment and its will to survive. He calls these 物理环境客观的现实与因果链条 (objective reality of the physical environment and the causal chain) and 智能物种与生俱来的任务与价值链条 (inherent task of intelligent species and value chain). An agent that exhibits these two conditions will be able to live autonomously when placed in a given environment and social group. In fact, the agent will learn the following: &amp;ldquo;认识世界、利用世界、改造世界&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We should all learn Chinese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/learn-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/learn-chinese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, my dad sent me a very long &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/-wSYLu-XvOrsST8_KEUa-Q&#34;&gt;WeChat article&lt;/a&gt;, titled “浅谈人工智能：现状、任务、构架与统一 | 正本清源”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loosely translated, the title reads: “A light discussion of Artificial Intelligence: Current Situation, Purpose, Framework, and Unification | Finding the root of the issue”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PI I used to do undergraduate research for — Prof. Song-Chun Zhu — wrote this 20,000+ character article. Prof. Zhu leads the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vcla.stat.ucla.edu/&#34;&gt;Vision, Cognition, Learning, and Autonomy Lab&lt;/a&gt; at the University of California, Los Angeles. In this article, Prof. Zhu takes us through the six disciplines of Artificial Intelligence (AI): computer vision, natural language processing, cognition and reasoning, robotics, game &amp;amp; ethics, and machine learning. He outlines the article’s purpose as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commencement speech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/ucla-commencement-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/ucla-commencement-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 17, 2017, I had the honor to speak about what being an Engineer means to me in front of 10,000+ people in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Pauley_Pavilion&#34;&gt;Pauley Pavilion&lt;/a&gt;, at the 2017 UCLA Engineering Commencement for PhDs, Masters, and Bachelors degree recipients. As the Commencement Student Speaker, I wanted to find a voice that resonates with all Engineers, and so I focused on the qualities that applies to all of us moving forward: Mentorship. Learning. Community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>左宗棠</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/chinese-life-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/chinese-life-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I completed my undergraduate degree this past June. Like many new grads preparing to work in industry, I feel nervous about making a smooth transition from being a student to being a working-class young adult. Where do I go from here? How do I live a good life?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last night, I found some reassurance in a quote by a Chinese official in the 清 (Qīng) Dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story starts with a typical post-dinner discussion with my dad. We enjoy sipping some tea and talking, usually about parallels between Chinese history with the modern society. On the topic of life advice, he told me an incredible quote by 左宗棠 (pinyin: Zuǒ Zōngtáng):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 qualities of self-worth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/self-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/self-worth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, my dad sent me a link to an excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.sohu.com/n/474235216/?wscrid=95360_5&#34;&gt;blog entry&lt;/a&gt; written in Mandarin Chinese. I have always loved the Chinese language for its elegant brevity, and this entry was no exception. In just a few lines of characters, it succinctly summarized 3 qualities of self-worth. I wanted to share this with my friends in the United States, so I decided to translate the entry into English:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Jon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/jon-stewart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/jon-stewart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The best defense against bullshit is vigilance. So if you smell something, say something.&amp;rdquo; — Jon Stewart&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Comedy Central bid its final farewell to comedian Jon Stewart on &lt;em&gt;The Daily Show&lt;/em&gt;. For 16 years, Jon scrutinized media, politicians, scandals, tragedies, and various controversies, using humor as his medium to give Americans a second lens into the world we live in today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was not there to watch &lt;em&gt;The Daily Show&lt;/em&gt; in the very beginning. I was not there to witness many of Jon&amp;rsquo;s greatest moments where he completely demolished biased news stations. I dropped in to watch some of his highlights online from time to time. In those moments, he, with his vein-popping, eye-bulging commentaries, completely captured my attention, and spoke with a witty eloquence that left me in awe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, my parents celebrated my birthday early, because I’ll be at college during my actual birthday later in January. Usually, I reflect about being 1 year older AFTER my birthday, but since I’ve been having this ‘early celebration’ for a while, so I thought I’ll jot down some of my thoughts about the big two-zero now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 is amazing. The moment when the tens-digit of your age changes is always a milestone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 brings much introspection. I am near the middle of my college career, and my thoughts about occupations, relationships, and ‘oh no what am i going to do with my life’ are all slowly conglomerating into this fantastic but subtle transition from teenager to adult.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 gives me strength. To my surprise. I feel more energetic now than I have ever before, but I have to give that energy direction and purpose. Kind of like an adolescent padawan — full of the youthful force, but not sure where to use it and how to use it correctly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 reinforces me to keep an open-mind. Looking back, all my life experiences — the places I lived in; the high schools I went to; the jobs I worked at — they all taught me one, simple, universal truth about human beings: we all have a story. Not necessarily a story to tell, but a story; it could be simple, complex, sad, happy, exciting, plain, but it is a unique story. Some told their story to the world and inspired millions of people; some shared their story with their close families; some kept their stories to themselves. Such a beautiful world we live in! Misunderstandings happen, and people are sensitive, especially among the young adult population; I aspire to be someone who is willing to listen; I aspire to be a story listener.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 scares me, just a little. Well. I guess I am not scared by the fact that I am turning 20, but more likely by the fact that time inconspicuously flies by. Time has an interesting property to be warped in our perception; I guess it’s not something that can be explained by physics, but it seemed like yesterday when I was posing for a photo in front of my kindergarten in China, before my first day of school. However, I believe time is fair. We all age the same; it is up to us to decide what we want to accomplish every year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turning 20 excites me. I look forward to all that I will learn, all that I will experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a great year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
